<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BitcoinZH</title>
    <description>China Talks Bitcoin</description>
    <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://bitcoinzh.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 20:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 20:41:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Haobtc on the blockchain debate</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;haobtc-is-striving-for-more-network-power-supports-bitcoin-supports-blocksize-expansion&quot;&gt;Haobtc is striving for more network power, supports Bitcoin, supports blocksize expansion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Haobtc on the block size debate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Bitcoin blockchain is PoW. There is only one. 51% of the network decide on the direction the blockchain will travel in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each and everyone can hold network hashing power. Let those who believe in, and support Bitcoin, hold hashing power on the Bitcoin network. The possession of hashing power is a statement on the future of Bitcoin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The reason China has over 50% of the network is that has a very optimistic view regarding the future of Bitcoin. We’ve invested a great deal of manpower, material assets, all kinds of resources, bringing the current total to over 50%. It’s absolutely not about control.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overseas Bitcoin supporters can equally strive to gain more network power and then possess that 50%, we’d be happy to see it. The PoW blockchain is the most equitable. All we have now is the result of our conviction and belief in Bitcoin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;China mining pools having in total hold over 50% of the network power does not in any way mean the entire amount is held in the hands of a single bloc. Within this multilateral and distributed holding, each voice represents different interests and demands.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are fully behind an expansion in block size, and would most like to see this achieved on the Bitcoin Core. Bitcoin Classic is also supported, it currently holds the largest degree of consensus of any proposal. If it’s a reasonable proposal that drives forward block expansion in a reliable manner, we can all support it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 闪电&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lightning&quot;&gt;闪电 (Lightning):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haobtc is in F2Pool. At the moment I don’t see F2Pool among those supporting Classic, but I did see Haobtc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May I ask, does F2Pool support Classic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If F2Pool doesn’t support, well then what? Will Haobtc switch mining pools?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by ahr999&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ahr999&quot;&gt;ahr999:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support @星空 (Editor’s note: The official Haobtc account)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 比科技熊小二&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bikejis-little-waiter&quot;&gt;比科技熊小二 (Bikeji’s little waiter):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 神鱼BTCer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;btcer-spirit-fish&quot;&gt;神鱼BTCer (Spirit Fish):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by P2PBUCKS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;p2pbucks&quot;&gt;P2PBUCKS:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 比科技熊小二&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bikejis-little-waiter-1&quot;&gt;比科技熊小二 (Bikeji’s little waiter):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@神鱼BTCer 🐟always travel in big shoals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 云&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud&quot;&gt;云 (Cloud):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the Classic proposal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by mkz899&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mkz899&quot;&gt;mkz899:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@星空 Send it to Bitcointalk, send an English version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 鱼殊&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;special-fish&quot;&gt;鱼殊(Special Fish):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope the final proposal is achieved on Bitcoin Core. Of course, if Classic is extremely reasonable and reliable, I hope they’ll do good work on public relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by Trueiron&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trueiron&quot;&gt;Trueiron:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you support something or not doesn’t mean much. What we need is people who can actually deliver the code! We don’t want something like BIP100, made a big fuss but in fact it’s just a proposal too, nobody wrote any code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/haobtc-blocksize-debate</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/haobtc-blocksize-debate</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shanghai Blockchain Hackathon</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;blockchain-techs-profound-impact-on-financial-sector&quot;&gt;Blockchain Tech’s Profound Impact on Financial Sector&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tl;dr: Over twenty geeks from around the world came to take part in the Shanghai Blockchain Hackathon. Although the blockchain is widely perceived to be in an early development phase, within 48 hours a number of practically useful applications were delivered according to plan. Whether in logistics systems or humanitarian medicine, intelligent asset management hardware or video supply chains, even random number generation, the innovative ideas presented an eye-opening experience for everyone in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackathon, which took place from 1/8/16 to 1/10/16, was a milestone in China. It offered corporations and developers direct experience of the blockchain development flow at a historically opportune moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deloitte and Wanxiang Blockchain Labs partnered to organize this meeting of blockchain developers and enthusiasts. The participants were divided into small groups for a period of two days, sent to bang their heads together and create blockchain applications. The projects were then presented with a focus on design and development processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representatives from Deloittes global cryptocurrency team and Wanxiang Blockchain Labs were on hand to offer mentorship to all participants. As each team presented their original applications, they were in with a chance of winning up to a generous $10,000 in prizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1/6/16 to 1/11/16, cryptocurrency experts from Deloitte’s Innovation Labs in the US, Canada and Ireland and, along with their colleagues in China, organized a series of blockchain events in Shenzhen, Shanghai and Beijing in the run up to the main event. These included a series of lectures, exclusive blockchain application research and training events. On the afternoon of 8 January, in an exclusive meeting led by Ms Yi Qing，Blockchain Project Manager at Deloitte Innovation Labs, Deloitte’s Chief Economist and Senior Cloud Engineers were at hand for a comprehensive presentation of blockchain workflows present and future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about ‘internet’ and ‘cloud tech’, what do we really mean? When we talk about disrupting the assets industry, what do we really mean? When what we are discussing is let loose on the current financial sector, what kind of sparks will it ignite? These questions all point to a single answer - blockchain technology. The blockchain, through a form of decentralization, collectively creates and defends a persistent database. This offers potential strategic directions to the financial sector, thereby attracting the attention of executives and investors across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a study by Magister Advisor, total investment by the banking sector into blockchain development in 2016 will be in excess of US$1bn. This represents the fastest development of any field of software. 9 top-class global banks including Barclays, Credit Suisse and Morgan Stanley have already joined an organization led by R3, aiming to set out standards and protocols for blockchain technology within the banking sector. On 30 Dec, 2015, NASDAQ completed the first securities transaction on a blockchain platform, a significant milestone in the decentralization of financial markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, blockchain technology is one which uses a distributed network of computer nodes to maintain a shared source of information. As each node keeps a copy of the full historical record of the database,  they contribute to protecting the integrity and accuracy of the data. Viewed through the prism of financial information, this means each node keeps a full copy of the distributed ledger, including the full transaction history of all network participants. As the copy held by each node is immutable, the totality of information can be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the encryption of blockchain data maintains its security - all transactions are recorded in this encrypted state, including time, date and ID. Once recorded on the ledger, the transaction cannot be deleted, undone or amended. Although all participants hold a full encrypted database, their private keys only enable them to browse information related to their transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before any transaction is recorded on the distributed database, it will undergo highly complex checks and verifications. The network is continuously monitored by its participating nodes, who receive regular updates on its status, thereby ensuring consistency and eliminating any source of risk. Because every node can identify and refuse to merge into the database any corrupted transaction data, blockchain technology itself really is capable of eliminating any corrupted data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through real-time monitoring, this innovative design ensures data is not tampered with, offering participants and interested parties a single source of truth. The blockchain is without doubt the only technology that doesn’t depend on intermediaries or third parties, but only its own ledger to show consistency of transaction verifications and accuracy of corporate finances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deloitte’s global cryptocurrency team, part of Deloitte Digital, counts over 100 members all devoted to researching how to use technology to raise standards of service, and exploring blockchain-based solutions for its customers. They are bringing together several leading engineering schools such as MIT, and diverse blockchain development teams to establish strategic partnerships. Deloitte’s focus on the utility of blockchain technology is not only to drive efficiencies for its clients, but also for Deloitte itself. Deloitte’s blockchain platform, Rubix, is the cutting edge of its Deloitte Digital consultancy service, taking advantage of the blockchain’s most avant-garde technology and use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rubix&quot;&gt;RUBIX&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deloitte Rubix was the first team created exclusively to research the use of blockchain technology in the financial sector, using its most avant-garde technology, business models and global development supplier databases. It has already, in partnership with institutionally significant banks, developed several blockchain-based applications for the financial services sector. Outside the financial sector, the Rubix team has also developed almost 30 applications for corporate planning， some at proof of concept stage and some already in practical use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the applications designed by Rubix, Deloitte’s Perma Rec blockchain application technology stands out. It’s a globally distributed ledger, which through financial reporting systems such as SAP and Oracle, increases transparency in buy-sell transaction flows. Finally, auditors can also use it for real-time data calls to achieve 360-degree operational status and automatize tax and compliance reporting, benefitting both clients and internal regulators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Deloitte’s China Eastern Regional Managing Partner, Mr Patrick Tsang, points out, this hackathon is just a starting point. All kinds of ideas based on disruptive blockchain technology are provoking keen interest, and in the foreseeable future will have a profound influence on a large number of industries within the financial sector, creating opportunities for cooperation across different areas of expertise, increasing efficiencies in resource deployment and assisting in corporate transformations. Whether by enthusiastic adoption or passive acceptance, it will upset the status quo in all kinds of industries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/shanghai-blockchain-hackathon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/shanghai-blockchain-hackathon</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lan Mao asks, what is a blockchain?</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;chehw1&quot;&gt;chehw_1:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain was invented by Satoshi Nakamoto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Bitcoin] = [Digital gold] + [PoW blockchain] + [P2P]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The “digital gold” referred to here is cryptocurrency, not electronic currencies based on a gold standard (E-money).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by chehw_1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blockchain is a ledger whose contents cannot easily be tampered with, its entries in a sequence that may not easily be tampered with. The theory and robustness are principally based on the maturity of hash algorithms. Its features include timestamping and a distributed database (for consistent ledger contents) with backups in different locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous cryptographically-based currencies replicated properties of money, managing to solve the problems of authenticity and ownership, but were unable to be freely transferred without preventing double spending. After A has given B part of their gold, naturally they can’t use this gold again. But with electronic gold, A could maintain a copy of the original which differed in no way from the spent gold. So cryptocurrencies require a unified database record and the authentication of every transaction, and can thereby prevent any double spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous cryptocurrencies depended on the provision of centralized databases by trusted third parties to work. This kind of of currency can’t break away from a dependency on trust, at most at an individual or organizational level. Only a hopeless idealist could believe it could attempt to compete with a national currency. It’s hard to imagine it ever being deployed in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the blockchain, from a technological perspective, does indeed achieve all the database requirements of a cryptocurrency. This is perhaps among the reasons for it becoming the subject of research of a large number of organizations (including banks). Being a distributed database, the blockchain gave rise to another question: among similar competing databases, how can one determine which is the most authoritative, the most ‘true’?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain responds to this question by distinguishing between different operational methods: the PoW method belonging to the P2P family, the PoS method, as well the as centralized “private chain” method. The primary differences between these three methods lie in how they regulate who gets to decide what is ‘true’: “private chains” are purely centralized control, PoS operates on the right of the group, and PoW excludes the need for control, propelled forward by market forces, or depending on majority consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Bitcoin] = [Digital gold] + [PoW blockchain] + [P2P]. This is the first time trustless digital cash and transactions have ever been realised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by a1379246856&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a1379246856&quot;&gt;a1379246856:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll do my best not to go into too much detail and to use the simplest possible language to decribe a little in theory how a blockchain works. I hope this quickly brings some degree of knowledge about the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the Bitcoin blockchain as an example, you can imagine it as a kind of public ledger. This ledger:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exists within each of the internet’s Bitcoin nodes, with each node having a full backup.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contains a record of every bitcoin transaction since its conception.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ledger accounts are kept in separate blocks, each block containing a part of the complete transaction record. Each block also contains the id of the previous block, thereby forming a chain structure which gives rise to the name blockchain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To create a bitcoin transaction, it’s sufficient to broadcast the transaction details to the P2P network. When the miners’ record of your transaction has become part of a new block on the blockchain, the transaction is complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by sumubaobei&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sumubaobei&quot;&gt;sumubaobei:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you, wikipedia?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by 芭比馒头&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;barbies-steamed-buns&quot;&gt;芭比馒头 (Barbie’s steamed buns):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ll do my best not to go into too much detail and to use the simplest possible language to decribe a little in theory how a blockchain works. I hope this quickly brings some degree of knowledge about the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorted, OP owes you 20 bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by bitbybit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bitbybit&quot;&gt;bitbybit:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;chehw_1’s explanation was the most well-defined, you could put it in a textbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by sider&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sider&quot;&gt;sider:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know, don’t ask such hard questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by Xseraph2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;xseraph2&quot;&gt;Xseraph2:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bow in admiration before chehw_1, every word is original, not one copied and pasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by idgui.com&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;idguicom&quot;&gt;idgui.com:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of the comments above are pretty thorough, so I’ll just give an easy-to-understand introduction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blockchain is just a chain where every block contains the entire chain’s full sequential order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of these words are problematic though: what’s a block, how do you form a chain, what’s so special about this chain anyway, what’s the point of it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block
This can be understood as a block of data, most of these blocks contain electronic currency data like bitcoin transactions, which address sent how much to which other address.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do blocks for a chain?
This is a little like pointers in the C language. Each block is passes through a hash algorithm, with the resulting value recorded in a block. Each hash must be written into the next block, and that block’s hash into the next, and so on. In this way, a long sequential chain of string data begins to form, namely the blockchain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s so special about the blockchain?
Bitcoin’s blockchain is decentralized. It can’t be controlled or altered by anyone. This immutability and complete transparency are the defining elements of the blockchain. There are a few knockoff coins which, due to limited CPU or highly-concentrated wealth, are vulnerable to data corruption. For these reasons, only the Bitcoin blockchain is truly valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockchain technology
Blockchain applications record data on the blockchain as a proof of its existence. Because of the blockchain’s mass consensus system, it can be used to issue proofs of stock and equity. There are too many blockchain applications already, you couldn’t name them all in a lifetime, but all this blockchain technology aims at decentralization and immutability. And for the moment, the only one which can achieve this is bitcoin. In a way therefore, you can consider all blockchains to be based on the Bitcoin blockchain technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by 510685947&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;510685947:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply it’s just a ledger. Whatever good and bad things you’ve done, like what you came to chat about today, did you have breakfast today, have you jerked off today, every incident is recorded. POW doesn’t have so much CPU it can’t be modified, POS doesn’t have so much coin it can’t be modified, it’s as simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: 510685947’s signature says “Thanks Satoshi, for bringing us together. Thanks 8btc, for letting us meet our bros from every corner of the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by zln0927&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zln0927&quot;&gt;zln0927:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is a token of value built on blockchain value. Other cryptocurrencies are also built on blockchains, although at the moment Bitcoin’s is the best.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/what-is-a-blockchain</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/what-is-a-blockchain</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
