<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BitcoinZH</title>
    <description>China Talks Bitcoin</description>
    <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://bitcoinzh.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 22:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 22:19:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How did Satoshi Nakamoto hide their identity?</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-satoshi-nakamoto-manage-to-conceal-their-identity-on-the-all-seeing-all-knowing-internet&quot;&gt;How did Satoshi Nakamoto manage to conceal their identity on the all-seeing, all-knowing internet?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/how-did-satoshi-nakamoto-hide-their-identity/2016-01-28-how-did-satoshi-nakamoto-hide-their-identity.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;How did Satoshi remain anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of cryptography, algorithms, economics and sociology, they were extremely advanced. There aren’t many people could invent the Bitcoin protocol and code its client implentation. How could they, in the midst of a community, invent and develop Bitcoin and keep their identity hidden?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet has developed into something so vast, it should be easy to find one person’s identity. Perhaps when posting articles online, registering domain names, releasing software, etc. they kept their IP address well hidden, but in an everyday setting, there’s no way something didn’t slip. They just never interacted with other people nearby? Wouldn’t the people nearby notice? After they noticed, wouldn’t word start to spread?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ceo-at-8btccom&quot;&gt;巴比特 CEO at 8btc.com:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-satoshi-nakamoto&quot;&gt;About Satoshi Nakamoto&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the members of the Cypherpunks mailing list, Satoshi was/were part of the younger generation (perhaps 30 when they first appeared). But they were conspicuous even on a mailing list that included Phil Zimmerman (PGP’s developer), John Gilmore (star employee at Sun Microsystems), Steven Bellovin (worked at Bell Labs, then Professor at Columbia’s Computer Science department), Bram Cohen (Creator of BitTorrent), Timothy C. May (Assistant Chief Scientist at Intel) and Julian Assange (Wikileaks founder). Although these big fish of crypto haven’t mentioned them explicitly, we can see from a few details in what esteem Satoshi was/were held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hal Finney (an inventor of PGP) was Satoshi’s earliest ally. He had the affectionate nickname of Watson to Satoshi’s Alexander Graham Bell.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In 2011, Wikileaks began accepting donations in bitcoin, to the great acclaim of the community. But Satoshi made a statement to say this was not a good development and suggested to Assange that Wikileaks not do it. Although Wikileaks later played down the incident, it remains Satoshi’s last appearance and hints at the influence they had over Assange.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Satoshi’s status was even higher than their forerunner in digital currency, David Chaum. You can see the kind of person David Chaum was very vividly in the 20-year old &lt;em&gt;Out of Control&lt;/em&gt; by Kevin Kelly, a star engineer biography like that of Steve Jobs. The difference between Satoshi and Chaum was that although Chaum didn’t succeed, Satoshi drew on the lessons learned. It’s perhaps for this reason that Kelly holds a negative view of Bitcoin, related to technical issues and anonymous marketplaces. Kelly was much grieved at Chaum’s failure, considering his great affection, so he never quite trusted Satoshi’s abilities could reverse that fate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto weren’t the type to be in awe of the failed senior generation of cryptocurrency masters, on the contrary he took exception to the idea that ‘most people nowadays are more interested in the 90s’ and in an email exchange with a researcher (the recently published Trammell/Nakamoto emails) emphasized Bitcoin’s self-sufficiency and teased the failures of systems that depend on third parties (like e-cash). I hope people can see the difference, and that people believe ‘I was the first person to realise what we’re trying to build is a trustless system with no third parties’. Satoshi’s self-confidence was evident at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satoshi’s reflection on the failure of Beenz, Flooz, e-cash, B-money and other digital currencies was that the primary reason was the centralization of their architecture. This was because once a digital currency was backed by a single company which closed down, or its transactions processed by a centralized server that was hacked, it risked a crisis of confidence that would cause it to implode. In February 2009, Satoshi wrote on an IRC channel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Governments are good at cutting off the heads of a centrally controlled networks like Napster, but pure P2P networks like Gnutella and Tor seem to be holding their own.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nakamoto’s achievements in cryptography were exquisite. He showed many errors once taken to be extraneous were in fact by design, such as the the hidden back door in the Koblitz curve, used by the NSA in cryptographic standards. Or that if the Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm were applied a further two times, it would resist even a quantum attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When publishing Bitcoin projects online, Satoshi would use meticulously prepared identities and domains. As early as 18 August, 2009, he had registered the bitcoin.org domain and bitcoin.net as a protective measure. The whois information has no value, pointing to a small ISP in Helsinki. The registrar info is for a small company named anonymousspeech.com. Why this choice? Because they claim to maintain client anonymity in domain name registration, guaranteed not to be found online or by government. Researchers have pursued this company but their efforts were fruitless. Because Nakamoto used Tor when sending emails, and because the rights to bitcoin.org have been handed over, which also explains how it ended up in Helsinki. But bitcoin.net definitely remains in Nakamoto’s hands. Once the domains had been set up, on 11 February, 2009 Satoshi published his Bitcoin project on http://p2pfoundation.ning.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significantly, on the Bitcoin genesis block, Satoshi recorded the inalterable message, “The Times 03/Jan/2009 Chancellor on brink of second bailout for banks”. This was that day’s headline from the London Times. This showed both the time of the first block’s creation, and mocked the weak systems of the crisis-stricken banks. It may just be a smokescreen regarding their true identity. Whose is the black hand behind bitcoin? People may have misunderstood the significance of the creation of Bitcoin. In the white paper, A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System, Nakamoto barely uses the word currency. Yet its timestamp was hinted at in that genesis block. It took a few years for developers to begin to understand the far-reaching significance of the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto’s actions were meticulously careful. In regular email correspondence he would use PGP and Tor. Gavin Andressen, Chief Scientist at the Bitcoin Foundation, once told a reporter, a lot of people claim to have received emails from Satoshi, but you can easily see through them because they haven’t used his PGP signature. Nakamoto encrypted all communications even with his closest collaborators and never revealed any personal details. Gavin, Nick Szabo, Hal Finney and others all know very little about him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handing the project over to Gavin involved just a quick series of emails. Given the FBI placed undercover agents to work on the Silk Road case, Satoshi was clearly far-sighted. He even planted a few false characteristics for people to follow up on. Errors such as English mistakes but GMT-based schedule, his Japanese name, using ‘we’ in the white paper, unfamiliar technical vocabulary, mimicking the style of his fellow cryptographers, repeatedly using ‘of course’ without a comma in different ways (the problem of course is), using the word ‘preclude’, which appears in less than 1.5% of cryptographic literature. These smokescreens met with some success, with many researchers and private investigators having searched for their true identity. There are tens of candidates including talented mathematicians, big fish the tech pool, the possibility of a team, but not one checks out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/how-did-satoshi-nakamoto-hide-their-identity</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/how-did-satoshi-nakamoto-hide-their-identity</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hard fork then 51% attack Bitcoin</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;core-devs-arent-refusing-block-size-increase-due-to-bandwidth-its-to-add-fees&quot;&gt;Core devs aren’t refusing block size increase due to bandwidth, it’s to add fees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About the author: I took an interest in Bitcoin and have held a few coins since early 2013, when under this username I began lurking around forums here and overseas. I wanted to say a few words about block expansion. This is the first time I’ve posted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/hard-fork-then-51-attack-bitcoin/2016-01-27-hard-fork-then-51-attack-bitcoin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Proposal to 51% attack Bitcoin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;foreward&quot;&gt;Foreward&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday on Reddit someone posted that for one core developer, Greg Maxwell, the main reason not to increase block size isn’t bandwidth, it’s because he thinks fees are too low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/btc/comments/42hl7g/greg_maxwell_admits_the_main_reason_for_the_block/&quot; title=&quot;Reddit post on Greg Maxwell&#39;s motives&quot;&gt;r/btc post on Greg Maxwell’s motives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/btc/comments/42cxl9/xtreme_thinblocks/cza9ddu&quot; title=&quot;Reddit post on Thinblocks&quot;&gt;r/btc post on Thinblocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving one stone causes a thousand waves. Immediately there was a surge of comments. Not only that, surprisingly even there was even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.8btc.com/bitcoin-kuorongbenzhi&quot; title=&quot;8btc post on motives behind block increase refusal&quot;&gt;a post on a Chinese forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post suggests that you could keep the block size at 1MB to force Bitcoin to become a fee network. Within China, it didn’t attract much attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-quite-different-posts&quot;&gt;Two Quite Different Posts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reddit is mainly for passing stories on, and because it’s repeating news obviously there’s some level of distortion. The users checked out the claims regarding what Greg Maxwell had said, and found it wasn’t:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the main reason not to increase block size isn’t bandwidth, it’s because the fees are too low&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but rather:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The block-size limits the rate of new transactions entering the system as well… because the fee required to entire the mempool goes up with the backlog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was interpreted to raise the issue of whether limiting block size was for the express purpose of raising fees. Although it was raised by a few people, Greg was particularly sensitive on the issue (and has since revealed himself as leading opponents of block expansion, saying in the end only Google will be able to run a full-node).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this there was no further response from Greg, although he continued to leave messages on other forums. The news began to spread. A few hundred responses came in, seemingly all in opposition. One was a thousand-word essay, earnestly advising saying Greg just to carry on coding, keep at his mastery of C/C++, not to worry about Bitcoin’s future strategy and commercial development. It really seemed like Greg had already become the most malignant tumor within Core. At this point I had to laugh a bit. The writers were, in the face of Greg’s consistent opposition to block expansion, certainly not happy, but many recognized the contributions he has made, and continues to make, to Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I came back to look at the Chinese forum post again, it too said support for 1MB hadn’t changed, that it was to increase fees. Among the comments, one said if fees rose 10 times then mining profits would increase 10 times, so the emperor was in no rush to help his courtiers. If that really were the case, why have the world’s miners one by one declared support for 2MB? Because in their hearts, everyone understands that simply raising fees would be tantamount to killing the golden goose. High fees would deter new users from joining the network, which could kill Bitcoin. The different altcoins mentioned in the article using spam attacks with dust transactions could use much better methods, such as a fixed minimum fee, and not sacrifice everything at the altar of block expansion. It’s simply not worth the cost. Currently, the Bitcoin network runs on fees. Transferring bitcoin certainly involves sending fees. What should be done is to minimize fee increases to the greatest degree possible, even reduce fees (this was the aim of a previous hard fork). By attracting more users and growing transaction volume, total fee income will also increase, and with the new cashflow generated, the bitcoin price would also go up. One proposal is to increase fees even in an unhealthy state, one is to gradually increase fees over time. It’s clear at a glance which of the proposals is preferable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although a forced fee market is a good idea, it wouldn’t be possible with just 1MB. The entire Bitcoin network still looks pretty small, it definitely needs to be given space, whatever it requires in the course of its development. And it won’t lurch forward on unsteady wings, too easily cut down on its way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Satoshi Nakamoto, the most important thing is the final outcome. The final outcome. The final outcome. The most important thing is that fees maintain the security of the Bitcoin network, which doesn’t need intermediaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-core-oppose-a-hard-fork&quot;&gt;Why Core oppose a hard fork&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only reason for block size expansion, the only one, the only one, the only one (say the important things three times), is that there isn’t capacity to increase the number of users. There are many reasons why Core oppose block expansion. There are many reasons why Core oppose block expansion. There are many reasons why Core oppose block expansion. Say the important things three times. Do you know why there are so many? That’s simple. Each time one is criticized, they can produce another reason, among which some are for opposing block expansion. Their words and actions are clear enough, their basic premise is opposition of block expansion. Their arguments all serve this end. At the moment, the latest argument is consensus. This was also the reason for a united post on behalf of the Chinese bitcoin community. Its author also wonders, if consensus is finally reached, then what reason will Core provide for refusing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-is-cores-basic-premise-not-to-increase-block-size&quot;&gt;Why is Core’s basic premise not to increase block size?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no harm in looking again at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@octskyward/%E6%AF%94%E7%89%B9%E5%B8%81%E5%8C%BA%E5%9D%97%E5%A4%A7%E5%B0%8F%E7%9A%84%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98-a4a25d30485f#.gsmpi2fy4&quot; title=&quot;Mike Hearn leaves Bitcoin, Chinese language post&quot;&gt;the article Mike Hearn wrote&lt;/a&gt; some three months ago. Mike may now be considered the traitor of the Bitcoin community, but the commenters believe he must been extremely disappointed to have taken this path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some concerns were also raised around Blockstream’s 2015 fundraising round, which means that within a few months its investors will be looking for an increase in value. By using this crisis to ensure their technology is essential, they’ll be able to increase their valuation for the next funding round. And an increase in block size would also mean a reduction in Blockstream’s value (just a small laugh for this, because it’s just a doubt). But if it’s true that Blockstream controls Core, then Blockstream’s future also depends on Bitcoin’s future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-there-any-hope-left-of-a-core-hard-fork&quot;&gt;Is there any hope left of a Core hard fork?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their previous statements show not all Core members are as obstinately anti-expansion as Greg. Some have even issued their own proposals for expansion, although stressing they were individual proposals. But Core has slowly been taken under the control of Greg, representing the views of Blockstream. So the commenters think the only hope is to reach a consensus and thereby force Core into doing the hard fork for an increase. They hope that once they’ve reached consensus, Core won’t produce any further arguments against expansion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;either-you-advance-or-you-withdraw-putting-excellence-first-isnt-everything&quot;&gt;Either you advance or you withdraw. Putting excellence first isn’t everything.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people think, Bitcoin stands for excellence first. However we to and fro, the status of Bitcoin among digital currencies can’t change, isn’t it? If we don’t act now to increase block size, by mid-2016 saturated blocks will be the norm. Users will face fees as the norm. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.8btc.com/opinion-2mb&quot; title=&quot;8btc article on blockchain fee calculations&quot;&gt;Another article&lt;/a&gt; looked at how fees are calculated. When we think of future application uses, like McDonald’s supporting payment by digital currency, where the item cost may be around $2 dollars and the fees are around 20 cents or more, if there’s a cheaper alternative such as Litecoin which supports bigger blocks, then people will prefer to use that. In an era when market cap determines winners, one can imagine Litecoin would then have a bigger market cap than Bitcoin. Ok, it might be an extreme example, but remember the scale of the crisis. Bitcoin’s ambition isn’t just to be a clearing network, it’s to incorporate everyday transactions onto the network too. If the ambition lies only in clearing, it’s highly possible we’ll crash during take-off. Because currently Bitcoin is too highly controlled as a clearing network. But if take a longer view, then even if we don’t become a regular everyday payments system, we’ll be astonished to discover we actually have something that goes a long way beyond just clearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more thing. Bitcoin is a technological product. To a certain extent, it’s also the product of our conviction. And having higher ambitions can give other network participants more conviction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way, Bitcoin is also a product of the internet and there are examples of products which were excellent but failed. A few decades ago, just before http, people went online using gopher, and http was just a gopher rip-off. Just like Bitcoin, gopher had over 90% market share. But gopher asked for fees and everyone knows how that story ends. If one these altcoins that exists today can be used for transactions tomorrow, and Bitcoin fees are high, as a regular or new user, why would I use bitcoin?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other examples include Myspace, Xiaomi’s MiTalk, FlashGet, Microsoft’s MSN. Too, too, many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-bitcoin-white-paper&quot;&gt;The Bitcoin white paper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three things that make Bitcoin unique &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/en/&quot; title=&quot;Bitcoin.org homepage&quot;&gt;according to bitcoin.org&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fast peer-to-Peer transactions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worldwide payments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low processing fees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If 1MB blocks are maintained, we’ll lose two of these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fast peer-to-Peer transactions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low processing fees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that the kind of Bitcoin we want?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-exactly-should-we-do&quot;&gt;What exactly should we do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s still about consensus. And the foremost consensus is among miners. In a crisis, consensus among miners alone is enough. So the miners must be active, communicate within the industry, build a community of over 95% of miners, set up a hotline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need deeds and not just words. Commenters are just common holders, they don’t have any hashing power just the hope that the miners will act quickly. In the event of the last hope, a hard fork, most of the hashing power will shift to the chain with big blocks. A 51% attack would depose the other chain, thereby maintaining the unicity of the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/are-small-blocks-a-plan-for-fees</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/are-small-blocks-a-plan-for-fees</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chinese proposal to reconcile Bitcoin</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;bitcoin-community-reaches-902-consensus-supports-2mb-blocks-rejects-any-fork-with-less-than-90-consensus&quot;&gt;Bitcoin community reaches 90/2 consensus: Supports 2MB blocks, rejects any fork with less than 90% consensus.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: ltc1btc mining pool founder, Jiang Zhou Er
Declared Interests: Bitcoin / Litecoin mining, currency holder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, Chinese text from 8btc&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the afternoon of the 1/23, on the coldest of days in Beijing, Haobtc organised a meeting to warm the spirits of the Bitcoin community through action. There was passionate discussion of issues including the development of Haobtc, expansion of block size, mining and the future prospects of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding block size, the participants reached consensus, and hope all Bitcoin companies and users will also join the consensus, around the following 90/2 proposal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin block size needs to expand to 2MB.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opposition to any fork with under 90% consensus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting participants:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Haobtc CEO, Wu Gang&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitmain CEO, Wu Ji Han&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Antminer Pool, Pan Zhibiao&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BTC123, Guo Hongcai&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richfund, Zhao Guofeng&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yunbi, Mr Mao&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bither, Wen Hao&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BTCKan, Fang Fang&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sosobtc, Lin Jiapeng&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Excuse me if any of the numerous participants have not been included.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;consensus-solution&quot;&gt;Consensus Solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we know, block size expansion is a technical issue, where personal interests have led to it becoming a political issue. For full background, please see the previous article, &lt;a href=&quot;/the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners/&quot;&gt;The Choices Facing Bitcoin Miners&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday’s Miami meeting didn’t lead to any substantive proposal or conclusions. As there is no consensus to fork to Classic, in order to a avoid division within the community we must put aside our differences and reach a more basic form of consensus. Core states that expansion without consensus is risky. If consensus is required, that’s what we’ll provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This consensus can obtain widespread unanimity, avoid division and bring reassurance to the market, and is flexible enough to be future-proofed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;90% consensus is sufficient to reject any potential community division and ensures security in the community will continue to develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consensus around 2MB has its origins in Satoshi’s white paper - “&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Bitcoin White Paper by Satoshi Nakamoto&quot;&gt;Bitcoin: A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System&lt;/a&gt;” - &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; A Peer-to-Peer Settlement System. According to Satoshi Nakamoto’s design, bitcoin is a currency and not a settlement system. 1MB is incapable of meeting the demands of a currency, and is even incapable of meeting the requirements of a settlement system (1MB = 7 transactions / second, SWIFT = 60 transactions / second).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome all Bitcoin companies and users to add to this basic form of consensus. For example, during discussion the following proposal was suggested:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If blocks are full, block size still hasn’t been increased to 2MB and the Classic proposal still hasn’t achieved consensus, and if the condition of 90% consensus is met, in line with the block expansion contingency plan by Satoshi Nakamoto in 2010 &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=1347.msg15366#msg15366&quot; title=&quot;Block Size Expansion Patch&quot;&gt;([PATCH] increase block size limit)&lt;/a&gt;, change a single line of code in the current repo to increase 1MB to 2MB. This would dissipate the imminent danger and provide ample time for the community to discuss the merits of various proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, it must be accepted, is a simple proposal highly likely to gain widespread consensus. With this kind of feasible proposal, we can cause/force Core to actively settle the dispute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-risks-of-segwit&quot;&gt;The Risks of SegWit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Core developers are attempting to use SegWit to indirectly increase capacity, but there are major problems and concealed security issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, if SegWit is used in 100% of all single-signature transactions, the maximum impact will be an increase to 1.6MB. Due to the complexity and enormous development work entailed by SegWit, it will be practically difficult for applications to update, and some may even be unwilling. If it is used in 50% of transactions, within 6-12 months we will have reached effective expansion to 1.3MB, which is quite insignificant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, SegWit means a major revision of Bitcoin’s base logic, huge development work and a high level of risk. Under pressure from the community, Core developers have clearly been racing against the clock. Bitmain CEO, Wu Jihan, confirmed this saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Under the circumstances, Core developers have been working well over ten hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many Bitcoin users come from a technical background. They know what kind of code is written under these circumstances of time pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the impression of Bitcoin as “stable and robust”, there have historically been several security issues. If SegWit is hastily implemented, &lt;strong&gt;should such security issues appear, Bitcoin’s value won’t just fluctuate by tens of dollars, it will be wiped out and the reputational damage will be long-lasting and nefarious.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, it’s critical we prevent Core from hastily implementing SegWit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;consensus-actions&quot;&gt;Consensus Actions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will spare no efforts in asking other Bitcoin companies to join in this consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite you to reply in the comments below [Editor’s note: 8btc.com comments, link at page head] indicating your support. Thanks everyone for supporting Bitcoin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further explanation: why 90% CPU consensus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because some miners do not belong to public pools (individuals or private pools), it’s difficult for this group to express their wishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excluding this silent CPU and asking for 90% consensus is equivalent to asking for 95% consensus among all public pools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by 水无魂&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shui-wuhun&quot;&gt;水无魂 Shui Wuhun:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a bitcoin holder and user, and I support this consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by satoshi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;satoshi&quot;&gt;satoshi:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a bitcoin holder and user, and I support this consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by 深水埗惊云&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;深水埗惊云:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a bitcoin holder and user, and I support this consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by bluestar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bluestar&quot;&gt;bluestar:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What good news - as soon as it came out the price went straight up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by jb9082&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jb9082-editors-note-this-name-is-rude-isnt-chinese-subtle&quot;&gt;jb9082 [Editor’s note: this name is rude, isn’t Chinese subtle;)]:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Classic instead of Core is the most appropriate proposal. I’ve lost confidence in the Core team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by 莱特币矿池&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;litecoin-mining-pool&quot;&gt;莱特币矿池 Litecoin Mining Pool:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reply to jb9082 above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everyone agreed with Classic, then it’d be simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Classic has issues with maturity and communication which led to some people opposing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now perhaps a good outcome has occurred: Core persists in not making blocks bigger, then mining pools with the assent of the community and in line with Satoshi’s contingency plan, change one line of code to upgrade to 2MB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Completely destroying this sole, central power of Core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by jb9082&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jb9082&quot;&gt;jb9082:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reply to Litecoin Mining Pool above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good plan!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by 恐龙化石&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dinosaur-fossil&quot;&gt;恐龙化石 Dinosaur Fossil:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reply to Litecoin Mining Pool above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Core have done a lot of work, they need to listen to the community more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinese voices can’t be ignored!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In yesterday’s meeting, Core said there was insufficient consensus, but the last 2MB proposal has the support of a lot of companies, miners and exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone agrees it must be on Core that the block size is expanded to 2MB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by yuli7376&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;yuli7376&quot;&gt;yuli7376:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“change a single line of code in the current repo to increase 1MB to 2MB”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aren’t there issues with upgrading in this way? If it wouldn’t lead to any harmful consequences, then it’s not necessarily out of the question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by sider&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sider&quot;&gt;sider:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only has support within China then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought the whole Core team had all agreed to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by sangzou&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I support Bitcoin Core!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Hasn’t Wu Gang [Editor’s note: Haobtc CEO, Wu Gang] already supported Core? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-core/website/issues/50&quot; title=&quot;Github Issue containing names of individuals and companies who have declared support for the Bitcoin Core team roadmap.&quot;&gt;https://github.com/bitcoin-core/website/issues/50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin/2016-01-24-chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-bitcoin-13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China proposal to reconcile Bitcoin, response by sangzou&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The community’s core devs have explained this issue very clearly: including Peter Todd, they have all signed in support of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoincore.org/en/2015/12/21/capacity-increase/&quot; title=&quot;Bitcoin Core team roadmap, Capacity increases for the Bitcoin system.&quot;&gt;Capacity increases for the Bitcoin system&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can I ask, for what reason do you not support them? From a technical point of view (serious).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/Chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-Bitcoin</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/Chinese-proposal-to-reconcile-Bitcoin</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The choices facing Bitcoin miners</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-key-choices-facing-bitcoin-a-request-to-all-btc-holders-to-support-expansion-to-2mb&quot;&gt;[The key choices facing Bitcoin] A Request to All BTC Holders to Support Expansion to 2MB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: ltc1btc mining pool founder, Jiang Zhou Er
Declared Interests: Bitcoin / Litecoin mining, currency holder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners/2016-01-22-the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The choices facing bitcoin miners, Chinese text from Bikeji&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without risk of exaggeration, the key choices facing Bitcoin are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Blockstream company has recruited a number of Bitcoin Core developers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Blockstream company has developed a sidechain for small transactions - Lightning Network&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the block size is expanded, small transactions will be possible on the main blockchain, and the added value of Lightning Network will be reduced, even eliminated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Core developers recruited by Blockstream have a long record of opposing any block expansion proposal - even to 2MB.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Satoshi disciple, Gavin Andressen and another Core developer, Jeff Garzik, are unable to convince the others, and thus formed the Bitcoin Classic dev group to drive forward expansion to a 2MB block, but the situation currently does not look favorable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners/2016-01-22-the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The choices facing bitcoin miners, Chinese comment image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@P2PBUCKS
The outcome of today’s meeting in Beijing is:
1MB, Gavin and Jeff’s Bitcoin Classic proposal did not gain Chinese support. Future: Bitcoin will become a ‘decentralized value network’, fees will increase, mining requirements will increase, the size of a full node will increase, large corporations will use Lightning Network-style solutions for transaction clearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners/2016-01-22-the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The choices facing bitcoin miners, Chinese comment image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@BITCOIN SAUCE
Foreceast: Stalemate for a while. Classic supporters aren’t willing to undergo a hard fork, will compromise in the end. Waiting for SegWit and LN. In future, there will be no further block expansion. The Blockstream company has completely won. Bitcoin thus transforms into low-level payment clearing, low-cost transactions move to LN and Sidechains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Gavin’s final efforts are unsuccessful, Bitcoin may be locked at a 1MB level by the Core developers for a very long time, possibly forever. It will become a kind of clearing house just like there are now between banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you and I aren’t prepared to spend a few yuan on fees, even a few hundred yuan, then we won’t be able to use the main Bitcoin blockchain. Bitcoin will be on the road to failure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, I will refute one by one the arguments of the 1MB block supporters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1MB Supporters&lt;/strong&gt;: Block expansion will lead to a reduction in the number of full nodes, reducing the security of the Bitcoin network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response&lt;/strong&gt;: Full nodes that run on static IPs and provide block data to other nodes, those that have no rights and can only contribute data, number 6000 globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main role of full nodes is to quickly broadcast new blocks to the network. But it’s not necessarily true that, because there are fewer full nodes, new blocks won’t be broadcast to the entire network. At worst it’ll be a bit slower, and you can’t say that Bitcoin just wouldn’t be secure as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nodes have no destructive capacity, any false information broadcast will be rejected by other nodes. The only harm a node can do is to act as a leech: only downloading and never uploading data, just like many of the nodes currently on the network. But this can only postpone, never prevent, a block being broadcast to the entire network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just like when downloading the Bitcoin client - if there are 6000 nodes it might be a bit quicker than if there are 3000, but it’s not to say that at a certain point it just doesn’t work, at worst it will be slightly slow to begin with then people will exchange more data to speed it up. It’s also not the case that, as with torrent files, the data would be corrupted or put out of sequence, both Core and Classic guarantee block data accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the number of full nodes has dropped a bit recently, the quality in terms of available bandwidth for uploads is only growing, following the development of Bitcoin and companies in the industry (mining pools, trading platforms, wallets, payments, apps, merchants) which are also growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The number of high-quality full nodes is ever-increasing. This has led a number of early node-adopters to notice their efforts are no longer required. If there are so many nodes on the network, it doesn’t make a difference if I’m there or not.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so the false impression of diminishing nodes can appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1MB Supporters&lt;/strong&gt;: Block expansion will lead to a reduction in the number of full nodes, leading to network centralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a laughable argument, it’s just like saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Not lowering the oil price is to protect the country from pollution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as outside the community, a lot of idiots cen’t distinguish Bitcoin from a Ponzi scheme or a bubble, within it there are those who can’t distinguish between ‘centralization’ and ‘concentration’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concentration is an unavoidable phenomenon. If you think decentralization is the same as ‘de-concentration’, then why don’t we start a new version and fairly distribute all Satoshi’s coins?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of core developers who still won’t accept a 2MB block, will force other users onto the Blockstream-controlled Lightning Network, which may be the worst of all centralization scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1MB Supporters&lt;/strong&gt;: If we expand block size this time, it will set an endless precedent. And if all transactions are on the main chain, only those with super-computers will be able to run a client. The ordinary laptop user won’t be able to run a client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response&lt;/strong&gt;: Firstly, this opposition is only to excessively extreme expansion proposals, such as the already refused BIP101. Of course miners won’t blindly increase until the network can’t support it, or they too would suffer (orphaned blocks would increase).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2MB is a highly secure size, for example F2Pool has said we could currently manage up to 8MB blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners/2016-01-22-the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The choices facing bitcoin miners, Chinese comment image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we don’t support either side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just say the size of block. Don’t say Core or Classic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8MB. At the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon 20MB will be no stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The current controversy is because Core won’t move to 2MB.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why not increase to 2MB? Because within a year or two blocks will be full, and if the network can sustain it we’ll need to move to 4MB, 8MB. For these few years, since the main blockchain will be available, few people will use Blockstream’s Lightning Network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Blockstream won’t spare any resources in their campaign to prevent any increase in the main chain block size, even if it’s only to 2MB, even if the current 1MB isn’t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, what would happen if we did put all transactions on the main chain?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moore’s law points to the rate of increase in network power, and humans are unable to interfere with such laws.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future, global population will increase to how much? 7bn? 70bn? Will it still be the case that each person can have up to 100 transactions per day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not possible that the Bitcoin network could ever be unable to sustain the weight of all global transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, one PC can easily hold the entire world’s ID data, in future they’ll be able to hold the entire world’s transactions. And that day’s not far away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supposing in the distant future 2bn people use Bitcoin. The average number of transactions per person per day is 3, each one at 200 bytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each day there would be 2bn * 3 * 200 bytes: 1.2TB of transaction data. At an average of 144 blocks per day, each block would be 8.3GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supposing each user were to download everything within one minute. They would then require 0.138GB/S=1.11Gbs of bandwidth. Even today this isn’t a huge amount of bandwidth, and in the distant future it’ll be even less so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if we ignore future technology, labs using single fiber optic have already reached 43TB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transaction requirements of 2bn people will be but a drop in the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1MB Supporters&lt;/strong&gt;: If Core continues to refuse expansion, then miners will have to hard fork to Classic. Hard forks are extremely dangerous, and Bitcoin’s biggest requirement is to provide security and stability. Other needs should be meet by applications such as Lightning Network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response&lt;/strong&gt;: Hard forks are not intimidating. Bitcoin has already been through several hard forks. As long as there’s widespread consensus, it’s really just a regular upgrade. Because there are currently two Core developers who are determined to oppose a 2MB block, it is indeed hard to imagine reaching that level of consensus, and it would indeed be the most risky of hard forks recorded. This causes fear in some people, leading them to be coerced by the Core developers into accepting Bitcoin as a simple clearing system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s hard to believe hundreds of millions of Bitcoin users could just be playthings to these three developers, isn’t it? &lt;strong&gt;To create anything, you have to take a risk.&lt;/strong&gt; When a woman gets pregnant and gives birth, is there no risk? Where did you all come from then? Isn’t it because your mother risked her life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto’s greatest creation wasn’t Bitcoin, it was what came after Bitcoin - the end of centralized authority over Bitcoin. The founder themselves stood aside. Now there is only one point of centralization, that’s centralization of access to the codebase, controlled by the Core developers. Absolute power leads to absolute corruption. If the corruption is not eliminated in its early stages and doesn’t spare those who blindly follow it, some hearts forgive and some hearts don’t forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because pregnancy is high risk, it’s accompanied by much preparation and planning. It doesn’t lead to people just not getting pregnant. A hard fork may cause panic and even a big drop in price, but that just means within the community we need more communication to achieve a more widespread consensus. Let everyone know something is going to happen, why it’s going to happen, let Bitcoin users push ahead and flatten the obstacle. And it’s not me who thinks it’s risky, what’s risky would be letting Bitcoin become a clearing house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metcalfe’s law states that “the value of a telecommunications network is proportional to the square of the number of connected users of the system (n2).”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The value of a network of 100,000 people is 10,000,000,000. The value of 10 networks of 10,000 people is 1,000,000,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many users will a 1MB clearing network have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clearing network idea is underpinned by all different kinds of Sidechains that can’t communicate with each other - what’s the difference between those and Paypal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that what our Bitcoin will be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1MB Supporters&lt;/strong&gt;: With just two devs, Classic will be a dictatorship in the short-term, in the medium-term lacks sufficient depth in development resources, and in the long-term has no plan for governance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response&lt;/strong&gt;: As a newly-formed group, you can’t expect Classic to have the same kind of well-established development team as Core. But since Core developers Gavin and Jeff were able to create the Classic team, why can’t any of the 300 contributors to Core continue to code for Classic? They’re not private property belonging to Core are they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Satoshi was coding on his own, was it an unstable dictatorship?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vision of a development is more important than its individual members. Even if Classic does nothing, it’ll still be worth a thousand Cores who want to turn Bitcoin into a clearing house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lao Tzu said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I will do nothing (of purpose), and the people will be transformed of themselves; I will be fond of keeping still, and the people will of themselves become correct. I will take no trouble about it, and the people will of themselves become rich; I will manifest no ambition, and the people will of themselves attain to the primitive simplicity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruling without action means allowing many little interventions to let nature run its course, letting the people express their talents and meet their basic needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Core don’t need to do any more complicated programming. Maintaining Core’s availability and stability is enough, let other features go on other sidechains. This is not to deprive Core of any usefulness, as all the work is transferred to those sidechains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin’s earliest block size was 33.5MB. The 1MB limit was just a temporary limit imposed by Satoshi to stop spam transactions corrupting big blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During discussion of the issue on bitcointalk.org, Satoshi provided a detailed method to deal with expansion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners/2016-01-22-the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The choices facing bitcoin miners, Chinese comment image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn’t think this temporary cap would be used by some others as a gateway to hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a long-term Bitcoin holder, I believe a bitcoin will one day be worth as much as a gold coin (CNY2m). I have a deep understanding of Bitcoin and I’ve been an evangelist for it on all the forums here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m very clear, refusing anything over 1MB is just one step from death’s door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one bitcoin is to be worth CNY2m, don’t you think it’ll be because to the future user base? A hard fork may lead to price fluctuations, it may.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But if we don’t have the CNY2m bitcoin fantasy, who’s going to stand up to miners taking 3600 coins or CNY10m a day, every day for the long-term?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long-term, the Bitcoin price would inevitably drop to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re no longer talking about Classic v Core, those are just minor details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’re talking about now is together as one calling for 2MB blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only if we persist in our consensus around 2MB blocks can there be any consensus. To be able to reconcile Core and Classic, to be able to avoid any hard forks, takes the courage of the young solider before the ravine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a small number of people fear a hard fork, it means either 1MB forever or else an even more critical hard fork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the wheels of history will continue to turn, but I know too how perfect things can be, and plead for good faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will use all the influence I have to make sure Bitcoin gets past this hell. And even if Bitcoin doesn’t make it past this hell and is capped forever at 1MB, I’ll know that although it was a beautiful dream attacked by losers, it will still shine a light over every bitcoin and every miner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/the-choices-facing-bitcoin-miners</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>People&#39;s Digital Currency: Weibo reacts</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;official-pboc-weibo-annoucement&quot;&gt;Official PBoC weibo annoucement:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, official announcement on Weibo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Request from the People’s Bank of China Digital Currency Forum, Beijing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The People’s Bank of China Digital Currency research team is actively intregrating key  domestic and overseas achievements and experiences in digital currency, building mechanisms that better protect organizations. We’re moving forward in clarifying our strategic objectives at the central bank, tackling the key technological issues and working to shortly issue a centrally-backed digital currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by Mysterious Youth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mysterious-youth&quot;&gt;神图青春 Mysterious Youth:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evaluation of the central bank on digital currency is:
1. It can reduce the production costs of traditional cash-based money.
2. It increases convenience and transparency in economic transactions, reduces money-laundering, tax evasion and other illegal criminal activity.
3. The central bank will increase its ability to control supply and circulation of digital currency.
4. It will promote the creation of a completely new financial infrastructure, optimizing payment systems and making settlements more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 黑锤子一世&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;black-hammer&quot;&gt;黑锤子一世 Black Hammer:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The People’s Bitcoin 😂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 007龙少 Young Dragon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;young-dragon&quot;&gt;007龙少 Young Dragon:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A centrally-issued digital currency, method to be determined, success to be determined, but from the point of view of economic governance - must be issued. Regarding Bitcoin, I’d still guess the government will allow diversity in coins, let people continue to research the area. They won’t knock it dead, won’t give it the big ‘that’s enough’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 007龙少 Young Dragon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;not-happy-in-fact&quot;&gt;我不是真正的快乐 Not happy in fact:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(@007龙少)：It’s in the essence of Bitcoin that it doesn’t require centralized authentication. This is only a central bank revolution!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by Victorwei&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;victorwei&quot;&gt;Victorwei:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if today’s the start of something sinister… &lt;img src=&quot;http://img.t.sinajs.cn/t4/appstyle/expression/ext/normal/e9/sk_org.gif&quot; alt=&quot;思考&quot; title=&quot;思考&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 飓风之王狗狗币&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dogecoin-hurricane&quot;&gt;飓风之王狗狗币 Dogecoin Hurricane:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve studied Bitcoin for a long time, taken part in the safeguarding of the Bitcoin code, been talked out of it by a lot of friends, been attacked several times, and I still have no way to prove this is in fact a major trend. But now that the central bank wants to issue a digital currency, it’s just the bro saying in a loud voice, ‘did you see? no need to doubt it ever again!’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 演闻先生&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mr-news&quot;&gt;演闻先生 Mr News:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hehe, Central Shanzhai Coin’s guiding principle is ‘rooted in the people, keeping the people secure.’ Bitcoin couldn’t stand the weight of something the size of Central Coin. Central Shanzhai Coin is maybe a bit more similar to Ripple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 几米多远&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-fars-a-few-meters&quot;&gt;几米多远 How far’s a few meters?:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If every country develops its own centralized digital currency, if each country fails to accept the others, then you should use a decentralized coin for exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 足以自娱&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;amuse-yourself&quot;&gt;足以自娱 Amuse yourself:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the renminbi has been converted onto the blockchain, it’ll be seamless to transfer between it and bitcoin, simple direct transfer. It won’t be like now where you have to have an account at the exchange, and at that point international currency exchange will be so much simpler!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has just increased the purchasing power of the renminbi on an international stage, it’ll definitely help the renminbi to appreciate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by kkkk1122988&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kkkk11229888&quot;&gt;kkkk11229888:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This must be due to the good research work done on the Bitcoin blockchain. If it’s good technology then we should just admit it. And invest heavily in R&amp;amp;D. Last year the American NASDAQ completed its first experiment in blockchain transactions, China needs to raise the game!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by zhuangyixia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zhuanyixia&quot;&gt;zhuanyixia:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is always in flux, good days may be bad days, bad days may be good days, does anyone understand? Whether you understand in time or not may be of no significance. The world has its own natural laws of development, living among one another and working in the present aren’t too far away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 方恨少的半糖主义&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lesshatredsemisweetism&quot;&gt;方恨少的半糖主义 LessHatredSemiSweetIsm:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let go and imagine: money slowly but surely leaves behind the era of paper cash, spending anywhere means using some kind of machine, like your phone or a wearable device. Through passwords or consent buttons, one-swipe payments. This is the same principle as payment by scanning a QR code, maybe in a few generations time cash will have disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by Yi Jing Ping&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;yi-jing-ping&quot;&gt;易经平 Yi Jing Ping:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome news. Indeed because it’s based on figures too, the objects that meet and merge in currency are also just data. A workable digital currency is a pre-requisite for bringing together the future internet of things and as it takes shape, and digital currency wins trust, fully distributed digital currency will also exist. And research into the distributed kind will inevitably impact upon Abelian equation-based applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 比特币资讯&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bitcoin-news&quot;&gt;比特币资讯 Bitcoin News:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shock! &lt;img src=&quot;http://img.t.sinajs.cn/t4/appstyle/expression/ext/normal/f4/cj_org.gif&quot; alt=&quot;吃惊&quot; title=&quot;吃惊&quot; render=&quot;ext&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people at the meeting included representatives from People’s Bank of China, Citibank and Deloitte’s Blockchain Research Team. Zhou Xiaochuan, Governor of the People’s Bank of China attended the meeting. Executive Vice-President Fan Yifei attended the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 你不知道我在想啥&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-dont-know-what-im-thinking&quot;&gt;你不知道我在想啥 You don’t know what I’m thinking:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the news item is short, the significance of this is great. This indicates that in terms of the problems faced by digital currencies, the central bank will behave only as a passive actor. Through this Forum, the central bank has explained and clarified one point: the central bank will maintain control over the right to issue digital currency, this element has been glossed over in discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also sends a signal: as long as your digital currency fits with the vision of the central bank, they’ll welcome your R&amp;amp;D. Any digital currency which goes against their thinking will have no market in the future, and may even be subject to attack!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by 神图青春&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mysterious-youth-1&quot;&gt;神图青春 Mysterious Youth:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BAT [Note: Baidu, Alibaba, Tencent] have just come along, now along comes People’s Bank of China again…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-china-to-issue-digital-currency-19.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by a旺财&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-a-wang-cai&quot;&gt;a旺财 a Wang Cai:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PBoC! &lt;img src=&quot;http://img.t.sinajs.cn/t4/appstyle/expression/ext/normal/d0/z2_org.gif&quot; alt=&quot;[赞]&quot; title=&quot;赞&quot; render=&quot;ext&quot; /&gt; Not just shouting slogans, taking action!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-official-statement&quot;&gt;The official statement:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/china-to-issue-digital-currency/2016-01-21-pboc-statement-on-digital-currency-bitcoin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China to issue digital currency, comment by a旺财&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;peoples-bank-of-china-digital-currency-forum-beijing-conference-center&quot;&gt;People’s Bank of China Digital Currency Forum, Beijing Conference Center&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016/01/20, the People’s Bank of China Digital Currency Forum at the Beijing Conference Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers and experts from People’s Bank of China, Citibank and Deloitte held discussions and exchanges around identifying a framework for the issuance of digital currency, advancing national currency towards digital currency, state-issued cryptocurrency and other related matters. Governor of the People’s Bank of China, Zhou Xiaochuan, was in attendance at the meeting. Executive Vice-President Fan Yifei was in attendance at the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the meeting, along with information technology and mobile internet, the evolving states of trusted and self-managed cloud computing, secure storage hardware and blockchain technology were raised, as well as huge changes to global payment methods. The development of digital currencies is presenting new opportunities and challenges to currency-issuing central banks. The People’s Bank of China views this with a sense of great importance. We established a dedicated research team in 2014, which was further strengthened at the beginning of 2015, which has completed extensive research into frameworks for the issuance and commercial operation of digital currency, the key technologies in digital currency, the ecosystem in issuance and circulation of digital currency, legal challenges facing digital currency, the influence of digital currency on the economical and financial systems, relations between privately-issued digital currency and statute-based currency, international experiences in the issuance of digital currency and other related matters, reaching the end of this phase of the research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the view of the Forum that, under the current state of affairs of our nation’s economy, exploration of centrally-issued digital currency is of great practical significance and profound historical significance. Centrally-issued digital currency can lower the high costs of issuance and circulation of traditional paper-based currency, increase liquidity and transparency in economic and transactional activity, reduce money-laundering, tax evasion and other criminal activity, increase central authority over the issuance and circulation of digital currency, better support the development of the economy and society and assist in the comprehensive implementation of a universally beneficial finance. In future, the systems of issuance and circulation of digital currency will promote the creation of entirely new financial infrastructures in our nation, optimizing payment systems and making settlements more efficient, driving increases in economic growth and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the request of the Forum that the Digital Currency Research Team at the People’s Bank of China actively integrate domestic and overseas achievements and experiences in digital currency, continue to push forward work on the basis previously established, building mechanisms that better protect organizations, moving forward in clarifying our strategic objectives around the issuance of digital currency at the central bank, tackling the key technological issues, researching the applications of digital currency in the context of diverse scenarios, striving to issue a centrally-backed digital currency at the earliest date. The design of the digital currency should have a basis in principles of economy, general welfare and security, with applications ensuring low production costs, widespread coverage, seamless integration with other payment tools, and in increase in the applications and dynamism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In driving forward work on digital currency, the People’s Bank of China has established channels of communications with other related international organizations and internet corporations, executing extensive investigation into related domestic and international structures and traditional card-based payment systems. The domestic and international guests at the Forum view this issue as one of great importance, and held intensive high-level discussions on related theoretical research and practical exploration into avenues of development for the People’s Bank of China.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/weibo-reacts-to-china-moves-on-digital-currency</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/weibo-reacts-to-china-moves-on-digital-currency</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chinese concerns around Bitcoin decentralization</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;core-developer-announces-bitcoins-failure-and-sells-bitcoin-now-bitcoin-is-controlled-by-china-how-do-you-see-it&quot;&gt;“Core developer announces Bitcoin’s failure and sells bitcoin. Now Bitcoin is controlled by China.” How do you see it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/chinese-views-on-bitcoin-decentralization/2016-01-18-chinese-views-on-bitcoin-decentralization.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chinese concerns around Bitcoin decentralization&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Ayu, formerly of BTCC and BTC38&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason Mike Hearn made such a statement is likely due to BTC XT, which he worked on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The XT project was originally to address the block size limit, which is increasingly a limiting factor as the transaction volume increases. This is the reason core developers demanded to raise the limit from 1MB to 8MB. Coincidentally, such a raise would also raise costs for miners, ergo the objection from the mining pools. It just so happened that many of the pools and miners are in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are competing proposals concerning block size expansion. Aside from XT’s 8MB, there is one for 20MB; Bobby Lee, CEO at BTCC, proposed it be raised first to 2MB and then to 4MB; some members of the community argued that the block size should be adjusted dynamically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is hard to determine whether or not XT’s 8MB is the most reasonable of all proposals, but it gained extra authority from the fact that its developers were some of the most senior in the community. This authority, however, was at odds with what BTC supposedly stands for - decentralization. As the major mining pools refused to adopt it, the project flopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember in 2012, Bitcoin experienced a similar crisis. At that time, the Bitcoin Foundation still had enough authority to influence the community. It responded promptly and released a new version, which won the support of the majority of pools. As a result, the problem was solved in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on this incident, the Foundation claimed that mining pools act as an intermediary between miners and users, alleviating the shortcomings in decentralization, holding the system together and improving its efficiency. When I saw this comment, I was a bit surprised. Isn’t Bitcoin supposed to be decentralized? If so, why should a small number of players be allowed to call the shots?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have moved on since then. The small-scale, home miners have been replaced by those who traveled far and wide in the pursuit of cheaper electricity and cheaper rent. As a result, the decentralized nature of Bitcoin diminished. The entire community, divided in the face of crisis, split while haggling over utility and cost. When geeks confront businessmen, the current situation may be inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with Mike Hearn on at least one thing, which is that Bitcoin is an experiment. The value of this experiment is that the technology is decentralized (at least it was at the beginning). In the past, we took it for granted that decentralization meant inefficiency. Today, this doctrine is challenged by technological advances. When Satoshi Nakamoto created Bitcoin, many called it anarchism. It’s clear that by now that anarchy has descended into a system of representation - so much for social evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ppip&quot;&gt;ppip:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh I remember now. That did happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cao-lianzhi&quot;&gt;Cao Lianzhi:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really is a bit similar to representative system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anonymous-user&quot;&gt;Anonymous user:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concentrated democracy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wild-wind-boy&quot;&gt;Wild Wind Boy:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decline of decentralization…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;xin-song&quot;&gt;Xin Song:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People need to be led after all&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zi-ming&quot;&gt;Zi Ming:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantages will add up over time. This is the inevitable consequence of social development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wei-zhenghao&quot;&gt;Wei Zhenghao:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very good analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lin-weixun&quot;&gt;Lin Weixun:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This evolution of Bitcoin is a good social experiment. The reality proves that anarchism can only exist on a limited scale. It is very difficult for it to survive in a completely open environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wang-siyu&quot;&gt;Wang Siyu:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anonymous-user-1&quot;&gt;Anonymous user:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is a perfect social experiment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;yang&quot;&gt;Yang:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very interesting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lagesi&quot;&gt;Lagesi:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damn, I can’t understand what he’s saying at all&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pengyiwang&quot;&gt;PENGYIWANG:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This developer is not a core developer and he’s only committed three fixes, which ranks him #89.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pengyiwang-1&quot;&gt;PENGYIWANG:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin has been pronounced dead 89 times since its birth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bashan-yiye-chuyu-jiao&quot;&gt;Bashan Yiye Chuyu Jiao:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a pile of bullshit. I still can’t see how it’s different to a pyramid scheme. For computers it’s constant processing, for mankind it’s gambling. It is a game. A game of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lv-xiliang&quot;&gt;Lv Xiliang:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Way of Heaven is to give the excesses to those who lack; the Way of Man is the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jiang-will&quot;&gt;jiang will:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing is the future of the internet. Bitcoin mining may evolve into globally unified cloud computing. The entire world would be one huge mine with one giant miner based on a script. This will solve the centralization problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kuangnanfeng-in-response-to-jiang-will&quot;&gt;Kuangnanfeng (in response to jiang will):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is complete centralization. The only mine would be the central bank of Bitcoin, responsible for verification, documentation and distribution of bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/Chinese-views-on-Bitcoin-decentralization</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/Chinese-views-on-Bitcoin-decentralization</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hearn: a global embarrassment to banking</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-death-of-bitcoin-is-a-legacy-banking-conspiracy-theory&quot;&gt;The “death of Bitcoin” is a legacy banking conspiracy theory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/death-of-bitcoin-conspiracy/2016-01-17-death-of-bitcoin-conspiracy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tmtpost on Mike Hearn&#39;s death of Bitcoin announcement&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New York, 1/15 Beijing Time, the Federal Reserve organized a meeting under the theme “Beyond Bitcoin.” One half of those attending were representatives of the Federal Reserve, the other half representatives of major banks and the blockchain tech company supported by those major banks, R3CEV. During the meeting, the R3CEV spokesperson expressed his views:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“R3CEV programmer Mike [Hearn] was originally an agreed member of the Bitcoin Core development team. He says the Bitcoin experiment has failed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The airing of these views in the New York Times under the headline “A Bitcoin Believer’s Crisis of Faith”, led to widespread agitation in public sentiment as efforts to understand the impact of the news led to a drop in the Bitcoin price from CNY 2850元 to CNY 2350元.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet the views are neither complete nor factual. As senior entrepreneurs and observers on the Bitcoin industry, we can inform everyone of the real principles underlying collaboration in the Bitcoin community. In a nutshell, this controversy appears on the surface as one between Bitcoin radicals and conservatives, whereas in fact it is an attack on Bitcoin spearheaded by major banks on behalf of the legacy banking sector, with the Bitcoin community attempting to defend its own interests. And this is not conspiracy, it’s an open struggle between two sides acting in their own interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mike-is-not-a-bitcoin-core-developer-and-furthermore-he-is-a-spokesperson-for-the-interests-of-the-banking-sector&quot;&gt;1. Mike is not a Bitcoin Core developer, and furthermore he is a spokesperson for the interests of the banking sector&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s firstly clear up the issue of just who Mike Hearn is. In fact, he is not an agreed Bitcoin Core developer. Based on https://bitcoin.org/zh_CN/development, there are six Bitcoin Core developers, absolutely not including Mike Hearn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/death-of-bitcoin-conspiracy/2016-01-17-death-of-bitcoin-conspiracy-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bitcoin&#39;s core developers, January 2016&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A computer programmer, Mike wrote a Java library called Bitcoinj. He develops third-party tools for bitcoin, and essentially is not an agreed Bitcoin developer. In the six or so years since he entered Bitcoin development, he has submitted 3 bugs related to Bitcoin code, ranking him #98 among all Bitcoin contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the following three views expressed by Mike, we can identify the role he plays within the Bitcoin community:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He once propsed to the Bitcoin Foundation a rollback function for Bitcoin, whereby when Bitcoins are sent they would be frozen for a certain period, within which the sender could reclaim them. This would remove the Bitcoin transactions’ essentially irreversible nature  and render limit the scope of Bitcoin’s freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He raised the suggestion of a Bitcoin node IP list, an attempt to separate anonymity from Bitcoin that met with fierce resistance from the Bitcoin community.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;BitcoinXT, which he developed, apart from supporting a blacklist, also supports big blocks.This would lead to an increase the the cost of running a Bitcoin node and a consequent reduction in the size of the Bitcoin network, allowing it to be controlled by large corporations and eliminating the decentralization that is among Bitcoin’s unique selling points.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As can be seen from the above, many of Mike’s suggestions were completely contrary to the ideas of Bitcoin. In fact, in light of both his words and actions, his voice is met with howls of derision by a Bitcoin community in which he is considered less than welcome. Further, his statements are completely in line with the interests of big banks (destroying in inability to control Bitcoin, stripping the blockchain of its current status as financial service), which may explain his recruitment at R3CEV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R3CEV is a blockchain company whose principal activity is developing blockchain-based technology for business. Behind it lies the support of forty-two major global banks including Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley, etc. Their aim us to destroy Bitcoin’s resistance to control and to separate blockchain technology from its current status as a financial service. This is like a thief who, having stolen Satoshi Nakamoto’s blockchain technology, now also want to kill that same blockchain technology. Previously, the advice given to the American government on how to destroy Bitcoin by 兰德 was to a basic strategy: discredit Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R3CEV’s CTO is Tim Swanson, whose attitude of hostility to Bitcoin has been revealed time and again in media reports where he claims it is falling behind, not worth interest. Much like the point of view expressed by Mike Hearn. In fact Mike was enlisted as Tim Swanson’s general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blockchain business, although seeking to destroy the most valuable blockchain in existence, is also creating its own, emasculated blockchain for the services of its clients. At the meeting on 15 Jan, the theme was indeed “Beyond Bitcoin.” In fact discussion revolved around the blockchain. During a meeting on the blockchain, for a blockchain company to declare Bitcoin to have failed can only be considered a declaration of war, absolutely not an accurate description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nobody-can-announce-the-failure-of-bitcoin&quot;&gt;2. Nobody can announce the failure of Bitcoin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 4 Jan, 2009, Satoshi Nakamoto completed the first Bitcoin client and achieved an operational status now seven years old. Nakamoto is Bitcoin’s creator and first core developer. Aside from Nakamoto, there has been a constant supply of excellent programmers entering the ranks of Bitcoin developers, contributing code and moving Bitcoin forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Bitcoin Core developer, however, is nothing more than a custodian of the Bitcoin code. This status does not allow them to decide on the future direction of Bitcoin, let alone to determine whether or not it has failed. The role of a Bitcoin Core developer is to add new features promptly and in line with the demands of the Bitcoin community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bitcoin code is open source, followed by thousands of programmers across the world. Even if a single developer were to be bought by a bank and ‘turned’, even if they introduced such as ideas as “rollbacks” and “black lists”, the community would notice, in the first instance, and then the new code would be rejected by both miners and nodes and the new client would not be used. The ‘turncoat’ would have no effect, as new programmers could simply duplicate the actual Bitcoin code and in turn become its defenders themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real Bitcoin Core developers are lining up on Twitter to expose Mike, the bogus core developer, as dishonest. Real Core developers are more concerned with maintaining network stability, they live on the level of code. They don’t have the wild political ambitions that would lead one to unilaterally decide on the future direction of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin miners are defenders of the Bitcoin network, one aspect of their work being account-keeping, the other establishing a secure shield for the network. As Nakamoto explained in the Bitcoin white paper, the most essential principle underlying the operation of the network is voting with network hashing power. Those who seek the authority to maintain the ledger must have the hashing power to make those decisions. Malicious actors on the network have no way to bypass the barriers created by miners and their network hashing power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After seven years of growth, the Bitcoin network as increasingly robust. Total hashing power now exceeds 1000p. Mathematics is the most powerful arm, and currently there exists nothing which could penetrate Bitcoin’s defenses. Bitcoin’s code base as been updated many times, from Satoshi’s Bitcoin-Qt to the current Bitcoin Core, always evolving and becoming more perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the 89th attempt to proclaim the death of Bitcoin on record. The reasons cited include technological factors, political control, personal disputes, media disputes. Bitcoin has never suffered as a result.&lt;/strong&gt; On the contrary, it’s growth is increasingly powerful. This time will be no exception. Any structure which plots to control Bitcoin can only fail.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/death-of-bitcoin-legacy-banking-conspiracy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/death-of-bitcoin-legacy-banking-conspiracy</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Haobtc on the block size debate</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;haobtc-is-striving-for-more-network-power-supports-bitcoin-supports-blocksize-expansion&quot;&gt;Haobtc is striving for more network power, supports Bitcoin, supports blocksize expansion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Haobtc on the block size debate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Bitcoin blockchain is PoW. There is only one. 51% of the network decide on the direction the blockchain will travel in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each and everyone can hold network hashing power. Let those who believe in, and support Bitcoin, hold hashing power on the Bitcoin network. The possession of hashing power is a statement on the future of Bitcoin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The reason China has over 50% of the network is that it has a very optimistic view regarding the future of Bitcoin. We’ve invested a great deal of manpower, material assets, all kinds of resources, bringing the current total to over 50%. It’s absolutely not about control.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overseas Bitcoin supporters can equally strive to gain more network power and then possess that 50%, we’d be happy to see it. The PoW blockchain is the most equitable. All we have now is the result of our conviction and belief in Bitcoin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;China mining pools having in total hold over 50% of the network power does not in any way mean the entire amount is held in the hands of a single bloc. Within this multilateral and distributed holding, each voice represents different interests and demands.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are fully behind an expansion in block size, and would most like to see this achieved on the Bitcoin Core. Bitcoin Classic is also supported, it currently holds the largest degree of consensus of any proposal. If it’s a reasonable proposal that drives forward block expansion in a reliable manner, we can all support it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 闪电&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lightning&quot;&gt;闪电 (Lightning):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haobtc is in F2Pool. At the moment I don’t see F2Pool among those supporting Classic, but I did see Haobtc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May I ask, does F2Pool support Classic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If F2Pool doesn’t support, well then what? Will Haobtc switch mining pools?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by ahr999&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ahr999&quot;&gt;ahr999:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support @星空 (Editor’s note: The official Haobtc account)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 比科技熊小二&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bikejis-little-waiter&quot;&gt;比科技熊小二 (Bikeji’s little waiter):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 神鱼BTCer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;btcer-spirit-fish&quot;&gt;神鱼BTCer (Spirit Fish):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by P2PBUCKS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;p2pbucks&quot;&gt;P2PBUCKS:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 比科技熊小二&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bikejis-little-waiter-1&quot;&gt;比科技熊小二 (Bikeji’s little waiter):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@神鱼BTCer 🐟always travel in big shoals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 云&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud&quot;&gt;云 (Cloud):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the Classic proposal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by mkz899&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mkz899&quot;&gt;mkz899:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@星空 Send it to Bitcointalk, send an English version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by 鱼殊&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;special-fish&quot;&gt;鱼殊(Special Fish):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope the final proposal is achieved on Bitcoin Core. Of course, if Classic is extremely reasonable and reliable, I hope they’ll do good work on public relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/haobtc-block-size-debate/2016-01-15-haobtc-block-size-debate-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to Haobtc on the block size debate by Trueiron&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trueiron&quot;&gt;Trueiron:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you support something or not doesn’t mean much. What we need is people who can actually deliver the code! We don’t want something like BIP100, made a big fuss but in fact it’s just a proposal too, nobody wrote any code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/haobtc-blocksize-debate</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/haobtc-blocksize-debate</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shanghai Blockchain Hackathon</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;blockchain-techs-profound-impact-on-financial-sector&quot;&gt;Blockchain Tech’s Profound Impact on Financial Sector&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tl;dr: Over twenty geeks from around the world came to take part in the Shanghai Blockchain Hackathon. Although the blockchain is widely perceived to be in an early development phase, within 48 hours a number of practically useful applications were delivered according to plan. Whether in logistics systems or humanitarian medicine, intelligent asset management hardware or video supply chains, even random number generation, the innovative ideas presented an eye-opening experience for everyone in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackathon, which took place from 1/8/16 to 1/10/16, was a milestone in China. It offered corporations and developers direct experience of the blockchain development flow at a historically opportune moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deloitte and Wanxiang Blockchain Labs partnered to organize this meeting of blockchain developers and enthusiasts. The participants were divided into small groups for a period of two days, sent to bang their heads together and create blockchain applications. The projects were then presented with a focus on design and development processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representatives from Deloittes global cryptocurrency team and Wanxiang Blockchain Labs were on hand to offer mentorship to all participants. As each team presented their original applications, they were in with a chance of winning up to a generous $10,000 in prizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1/6/16 to 1/11/16, cryptocurrency experts from Deloitte’s Innovation Labs in the US, Canada and Ireland and, along with their colleagues in China, organized a series of blockchain events in Shenzhen, Shanghai and Beijing in the run up to the main event. These included a series of lectures, exclusive blockchain application research and training events. On the afternoon of 8 January, in an exclusive meeting led by Ms Yi Qing，Blockchain Project Manager at Deloitte Innovation Labs, Deloitte’s Chief Economist and Senior Cloud Engineers were at hand for a comprehensive presentation of blockchain workflows present and future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about ‘internet’ and ‘cloud tech’, what do we really mean? When we talk about disrupting the assets industry, what do we really mean? When what we are discussing is let loose on the current financial sector, what kind of sparks will it ignite? These questions all point to a single answer - blockchain technology. The blockchain, through a form of decentralization, collectively creates and defends a persistent database. This offers potential strategic directions to the financial sector, thereby attracting the attention of executives and investors across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a study by Magister Advisor, total investment by the banking sector into blockchain development in 2016 will be in excess of US$1bn. This represents the fastest development of any field of software. 9 top-class global banks including Barclays, Credit Suisse and Morgan Stanley have already joined an organization led by R3, aiming to set out standards and protocols for blockchain technology within the banking sector. On 30 Dec, 2015, NASDAQ completed the first securities transaction on a blockchain platform, a significant milestone in the decentralization of financial markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, blockchain technology is one which uses a distributed network of computer nodes to maintain a shared source of information. As each node keeps a copy of the full historical record of the database,  they contribute to protecting the integrity and accuracy of the data. Viewed through the prism of financial information, this means each node keeps a full copy of the distributed ledger, including the full transaction history of all network participants. As the copy held by each node is immutable, the totality of information can be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the encryption of blockchain data maintains its security - all transactions are recorded in this encrypted state, including time, date and ID. Once recorded on the ledger, the transaction cannot be deleted, undone or amended. Although all participants hold a full encrypted database, their private keys only enable them to browse information related to their transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before any transaction is recorded on the distributed database, it will undergo highly complex checks and verifications. The network is continuously monitored by its participating nodes, who receive regular updates on its status, thereby ensuring consistency and eliminating any source of risk. Because every node can identify and refuse to merge into the database any corrupted transaction data, blockchain technology itself really is capable of eliminating any corrupted data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through real-time monitoring, this innovative design ensures data is not tampered with, offering participants and interested parties a single source of truth. The blockchain is without doubt the only technology that doesn’t depend on intermediaries or third parties, but only its own ledger to show consistency of transaction verifications and accuracy of corporate finances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deloitte’s global cryptocurrency team, part of Deloitte Digital, counts over 100 members all devoted to researching how to use technology to raise standards of service, and exploring blockchain-based solutions for its customers. They are bringing together several leading engineering schools such as MIT, and diverse blockchain development teams to establish strategic partnerships. Deloitte’s focus on the utility of blockchain technology is not only to drive efficiencies for its clients, but also for Deloitte itself. Deloitte’s blockchain platform, Rubix, is the cutting edge of its Deloitte Digital consultancy service, taking advantage of the blockchain’s most avant-garde technology and use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rubix&quot;&gt;RUBIX&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deloitte Rubix was the first team created exclusively to research the use of blockchain technology in the financial sector, using its most avant-garde technology, business models and global development supplier databases. It has already, in partnership with institutionally significant banks, developed several blockchain-based applications for the financial services sector. Outside the financial sector, the Rubix team has also developed almost 30 applications for corporate planning， some at proof of concept stage and some already in practical use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the applications designed by Rubix, Deloitte’s Perma Rec blockchain application technology stands out. It’s a globally distributed ledger, which through financial reporting systems such as SAP and Oracle, increases transparency in buy-sell transaction flows. Finally, auditors can also use it for real-time data calls to achieve 360-degree operational status and automatize tax and compliance reporting, benefitting both clients and internal regulators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Deloitte’s China Eastern Regional Managing Partner, Mr Patrick Tsang, points out, this hackathon is just a starting point. All kinds of ideas based on disruptive blockchain technology are provoking keen interest, and in the foreseeable future will have a profound influence on a large number of industries within the financial sector, creating opportunities for cooperation across different areas of expertise, increasing efficiencies in resource deployment and assisting in corporate transformations. Whether by enthusiastic adoption or passive acceptance, it will upset the status quo in all kinds of industries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/shanghai-blockchain-hackathon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/shanghai-blockchain-hackathon</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lan Mao asks, what is a blockchain?</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;chehw1&quot;&gt;chehw_1:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain was invented by Satoshi Nakamoto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Bitcoin] = [Digital gold] + [PoW blockchain] + [P2P]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The “digital gold” referred to here is cryptocurrency, not electronic currencies based on a gold standard (E-money).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by chehw_1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blockchain is a ledger whose contents cannot easily be tampered with, its entries in a sequence that may not easily be tampered with. The theory and robustness are principally based on the maturity of hash algorithms. Its features include timestamping and a distributed database (for consistent ledger contents) with backups in different locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous cryptographically-based currencies replicated properties of money, managing to solve the problems of authenticity and ownership, but were unable to be freely transferred without preventing double spending. After A has given B part of their gold, naturally they can’t use this gold again. But with electronic gold, A could maintain a copy of the original which differed in no way from the spent gold. So cryptocurrencies require a unified database record and the authentication of every transaction, and can thereby prevent any double spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous cryptocurrencies depended on the provision of centralized databases by trusted third parties to work. This kind of of currency can’t break away from a dependency on trust, at most at an individual or organizational level. Only a hopeless idealist could believe it could attempt to compete with a national currency. It’s hard to imagine it ever being deployed in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the blockchain, from a technological perspective, does indeed achieve all the database requirements of a cryptocurrency. This is perhaps among the reasons for it becoming the subject of research of a large number of organizations (including banks). Being a distributed database, the blockchain gave rise to another question: among similar competing databases, how can one determine which is the most authoritative, the most ‘true’?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain responds to this question by distinguishing between different operational methods: the PoW method belonging to the P2P family, the PoS method, as well the as centralized “private chain” method. The primary differences between these three methods lie in how they regulate who gets to decide what is ‘true’: “private chains” are purely centralized control, PoS operates on the right of the group, and PoW excludes the need for control, propelled forward by market forces, or depending on majority consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Bitcoin] = [Digital gold] + [PoW blockchain] + [P2P]. This is the first time trustless digital cash and transactions have ever been realised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by a1379246856&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a1379246856&quot;&gt;a1379246856:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll do my best not to go into too much detail and to use the simplest possible language to decribe a little in theory how a blockchain works. I hope this quickly brings some degree of knowledge about the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the Bitcoin blockchain as an example, you can imagine it as a kind of public ledger. This ledger:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exists within each of the internet’s Bitcoin nodes, with each node having a full backup.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contains a record of every bitcoin transaction since its conception.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ledger accounts are kept in separate blocks, each block containing a part of the complete transaction record. Each block also contains the id of the previous block, thereby forming a chain structure which gives rise to the name blockchain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To create a bitcoin transaction, it’s sufficient to broadcast the transaction details to the P2P network. When the miners’ record of your transaction has become part of a new block on the blockchain, the transaction is complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by sumubaobei&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sumubaobei&quot;&gt;sumubaobei:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you, wikipedia?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by 芭比馒头&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;barbies-steamed-buns&quot;&gt;芭比馒头 (Barbie’s steamed buns):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ll do my best not to go into too much detail and to use the simplest possible language to decribe a little in theory how a blockchain works. I hope this quickly brings some degree of knowledge about the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorted, OP owes you 20 bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by bitbybit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bitbybit&quot;&gt;bitbybit:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;chehw_1’s explanation was the most well-defined, you could put it in a textbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by sider&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sider&quot;&gt;sider:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know, don’t ask such hard questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by Xseraph2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;xseraph2&quot;&gt;Xseraph2:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bow in admiration before chehw_1, every word is original, not one copied and pasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by idgui.com&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;idguicom&quot;&gt;idgui.com:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of the comments above are pretty thorough, so I’ll just give an easy-to-understand introduction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blockchain is just a chain where every block contains the entire chain’s full sequential order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of these words are problematic though: what’s a block, how do you form a chain, what’s so special about this chain anyway, what’s the point of it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block
This can be understood as a block of data, most of these blocks contain electronic currency data like bitcoin transactions, which address sent how much to which other address.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do blocks for a chain?
This is a little like pointers in the C language. Each block is passes through a hash algorithm, with the resulting value recorded in a block. Each hash must be written into the next block, and that block’s hash into the next, and so on. In this way, a long sequential chain of string data begins to form, namely the blockchain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s so special about the blockchain?
Bitcoin’s blockchain is decentralized. It can’t be controlled or altered by anyone. This immutability and complete transparency are the defining elements of the blockchain. There are a few knockoff coins which, due to limited CPU or highly-concentrated wealth, are vulnerable to data corruption. For these reasons, only the Bitcoin blockchain is truly valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockchain technology
Blockchain applications record data on the blockchain as a proof of its existence. Because of the blockchain’s mass consensus system, it can be used to issue proofs of stock and equity. There are too many blockchain applications already, you couldn’t name them all in a lifetime, but all this blockchain technology aims at decentralization and immutability. And for the moment, the only one which can achieve this is bitcoin. In a way therefore, you can consider all blockchains to be based on the Bitcoin blockchain technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by 510685947&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;510685947:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply it’s just a ledger. Whatever good and bad things you’ve done, like what you came to chat about today, did you have breakfast today, have you jerked off today, every incident is recorded. POW doesn’t have so much CPU it can’t be modified, POS doesn’t have so much coin it can’t be modified, it’s as simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: 510685947’s signature says “Thanks Satoshi, for bringing us together. Thanks 8btc, for letting us meet our bros from every corner of the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bitcoinzh.com/images/translations/what-is-a-blockchain/2016-01-11-what-is-a-blockchain-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Response to What A BlockChain Is by zln0927&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zln0927&quot;&gt;zln0927:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is a token of value built on blockchain value. Other cryptocurrencies are also built on blockchains, although at the moment Bitcoin’s is the best.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://bitcoinzh.com/what-is-a-blockchain</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitcoinzh.com/what-is-a-blockchain</guid>
        
        
        <category>china-talks-bitcoin</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
